## Kayvan Kazeminejad



### **Profile Summary**

I am an experienced *developer* and *architect* with over 25+ years of experience in a variety of platforms and programming languages including:

Haskell, Rust, PureScript, Scala, NixOS, Plutus, Solidity, C/C++. I have worked in several industries including:

Blockchain, Banking and Finance, Healthcare, Music, and Video streaming, Entertainment, IoT, Hardware manufacturing, and Military.

I love programming in Haskell.

#### **Contact details**

\* +1 415 636 1124

kayvank

in kayvankazeminejad

☆ San Francisco, CA USA

#### Technical skills

- Haskell, Rust, PureScript, NixOS, Scala,
- Kubernetes, Helm charts, AWS, GCP, Terraform
- PostgreSQL, Redshift, Big Query, MongoDB, Redis, Apache Spark, Flink, Elasticsearch

#### Soft skills

- Collaborate effectively with coworkers to reach shared goals
- Resilient, Respectful, and eager to learn new skills

### EXPERIENCE

#### HASKELL DEVELOPER at IOHK (Remote)

2023.09-Present

- $\diamond$  Design and implementation of the PlutusApps Marconi chain-indexer tool. The tool was used by several IOHK teams, including PartnerChains and dJeds teams, improving their productivity by +15%
- $\diamond$  Redesigned Partner-Chain's Trustless Haskell, PureScript, and Plutus smart contracts, improving integration time with non-IOHK blockchains by +12%
- $\diamond$  Haskell and Plutus contribution to the design and implementation of dJed StableCoin, which allowed early release of the StableCoin Pricing-Oracle
- Contributed to the design and implementation of the Innovations fastBft Consensus Rust platform, which led to the adoption of the fastBft consensus by the Midnight blockchain

### HASKELL DEVELOPER at Soostone (Remote). 2021.03-2023.09

- $\diamond$  Contributed to the development of the napkin, a SQL meta-programming environment that accelerates data engineering efforts by +30% across multiple backends (e.g. BigQuery and Redshift)
- ♦ Design and implementation of the OAuth 2.0 flow for the "napkin" project, resulting in a much smoother user experience
- $\diamond$  Contribute to replacing the legacy Monad stack with a Polysemy effect system, resulting in a more maintainable and flexible architecture, hence reducing time to market

#### SENIOR CONSULTANT at *Trucklabs* (Remote). 2020.03–2021.02

- $\diamond$  Implemented data ingestion pipelines using Scala and Apache Kafka to stream IoT sensor data into AWS DynamoDB, enabling real-time analytics dashboards for 200+ clients
- $\diamond$  Implemented multiple user-facing APIs, including smart-trucks routing, fuel consumption, and ETA estimation. These contributions resulted in reducing the fuel consumption by 11% while increasing driver retention by 27%
- ♦ Scala, Apache Flink, Apache Spark, ElasticSearch, Redshift, DynamoDB, Node.js

#### SENIOR CONSULTANT at RChain (Remote). 2018.04–2020.03

- $\diamond$  Design and implementation of rSong, an on-chain music dApp that was showcased at MIT-Media-Lab as well as RCon3, the dApp was downloaded several thousand times
- ♦ Contribute to the design and implementation of rSpace, a Scala implementation of Tuple-Space used for RHolang smart-contracts storage layer
- ♦ Scala, Node.js, Python, RHolang smart-contracts, Kubernetes, Helm charts

#### SENIOR CONSULTANT at Vevo (San Francisco, CA). 2015.11–2018.04

- $\diamond$  Engineered the cloud-based data services enabling Vevo's music recommendation engine to improve user retention by 17%
- $\diamond$  Developed HTTP APIs and several JSON-RPC services using Http4s, providing data services to downstream teams as well as Vevo clients
- Mentor junior developers
- ♦ Scala, Node.js, Python, Kubernetes, Helm charts, Terraform, AWS Serverless

### SENIOR CONSULTANT at Intel(Santa Clara, CA). 2013.09–2015.11

- $\diamond$  Design and implementation of VoD, Video on Demand, workflow for video assets encoding/decoding clusters, resulting in decreased video broadcast time by 39%
- $\diamond$  Contributed to the design and implementation of the VoD encoder/decoder of video assets in C++ to take advantage of the new clusters, decreasing decoding time by 37%
- $\diamond$  Design and implementation of the VoD reporting system, providing real-time status reporting of the transcoders pipeline
- ♦ Scala, C++, Terraform, MongoDB, Cassandra, ElasticSearch, Kafka

## CONSULTANT at Various locations

2000-01-2013.09

I worked as a consultant in various industries, including Banking, Finance, Healthcare, Defense, Hardware manufacturing, and Government

Kayvan	Kazer	mina	piad
rtayvan	ITUZCI	шш	cjuu

# Curriculum Vitae

## EDUCATION

California State University, Sacramento.
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Mathematics

1994–1999

# Certi<u>fications</u>

- ♦ Database Administration, *Northrop Grumman*
- ♦ NETWORK ADMINISTRATION, Northrop Grumman.
- ♦ ADVANCED NETWORK PROGRAMMING, Northrop Grumman.
- ♦ GAME THEORY, Coursera.
- ♦ CRYPTOGRAPHY, Coursera.
- ♦ Solidity, *Alchemy*.
- ♦ Plutus, Pioneer program, as well as Plutus Project-Based Learning, PPL.

## HOBBIES

I am an Endurance Athlete, and have completed several IRONMAN